Email: <a href="mailto:hello@mttjns.co.uk">hello@mttjns.co.uk</a>
Phone: 07766257577

Portfolio: <a href="mailto:www.mttjns.co.uk">www.mttjns.co.uk</a>

# Matt Jones.

I am a junior software developer transitioning from a background in engineering project management, with over seven years of experience encompassing transferable skills in project and people management, job planning, and facilitation.

Throughout my career, I have worked on projects following both Waterfall and Agile methodologies, allowing me to adapt to different working environments and collaborate effectively within multi-level and multi-disciplinary teams.

I am thrilled about the opportunity to leverage my skills and experience to create meaningful technology that positively impacts people's lives.

# Projects:

Name	Description	Tech/tools
"The London Underground Orchestro"	A front end web application utilising the TfL (Transport for London) API to transform live train arrival data into an engaging and interactive audio and visual experience. The train arrival information called from the API is sonified and mapped to the underground network, where notes have been assigned to each station and instruments to each of the lines.	Javascript, Tone.js, React, Node
<u>"Moangoose"</u>	A Facebook-like full stack CRUD web application that allows users to create accounts, post 'moans' and post comments on other 'moans'. The information is stored on a linked database that stores user information, posts, and comments.	Javascript, MongoDB, Express, React, Node
<u>"LairBnB"</u>	An <i>AirBnB-Style</i> full stack web application with a Ruby backend that allows users to create and list spaces, and to request bookings on listed spaces.	Ruby, Sinatra, Postgres, SQL, RSpec
<u>"Storyteller Dice"</u>	A frontend web application that combines the element of chance with AI language generation. It generates a set of six images from a pool of thirty-six options and uses the GPT3.5 API to craft unique stories based on the selected images.	Javascript, JSX, React, GPT3.5 Generative Text, REST API
"Me, The Machine, and Edgar"	Unity 2D Game Project in which I collaborated with a machine learning model I trained on the complete works of Edgar Allan Poe. Using the model as a collaborative partner, I created a new and unique story experience based on the works of Poe. This project aimed to provoke discussion on the concept of authorship in the era of artificial intelligence.	C#, Javascript, Python, Unity, ML5.js, P5.js, Style Transfer, Generative Text, WebGL
<u>"Bruno"</u>	A physical computing project exploring anthropomorphism, using Arduino and C++ I created a small 'robot' that displays the symptoms of social anxieties. The aim of the project was to analyse why people attach human emotions and feelings to objects that, outwardly, display no human features. The project was displayed at the Goldsmiths 'Mung' midterm show.	C++, Arduino, Physical Computing
<u>"Self Portrait"</u>	A creative computing piece written in C++ using OpenFrameworks, where a digitally generated random 'noise' pattern serves as a digital mirror to explore the relationship between the artist and their art. This project questions the conventional roles by reversing the artist's position, as they become a medium through which the computer creates the final artwork.	C++, OpenFrameworks

Email: hello@mttjns.co.uk Phone: 07766257577 Portfolio: www.mttjns.co.uk

#### Education:

Makers Academy (March 2023 to June 2023)

- → Software Development Bootcamp
  - Conducting pairing sessions to effectively solve problems using teamwork and communication.
  - Collaborating with teams to build web applications in an Agile software development environment.
  - Utilising Ruby and Javascript and practising Test-Driven Development (TDD) with RSpec and Jest
  - Developing responsive user interfaces using JavaScript, React, and CSS, and effectively managing code versioning with Git and GitHub.
  - Designing and implementing a scalable CRUD (Create, Read, Update, Delete) applications using the MERN (MongoDB, Express, React, Node) stack.

## Goldsmiths, University of London (September 2021)

- → MA Independent Games and Playable Experience Design
  - Developing successful game projects in Unity using C#.
  - Utilising C++ in OpenFrameworks creative computing and Arduino physical computing projects.
  - Using ML5.js and P5.js libraries to implement machine learning and creative coding projects.
  - Participating in Game Jams with teams and individually to produce projects to tight deadlines.

**University of Central Lancashire** (September 2004 to May 2009)

→ BA(Hons) Criminology & Criminal Justice

Weymouth College (2002-2004), Budmouth Technology College (1996-2002)

→ A/As and GCSE Levels: A-C inclusive of English, Maths, Computing and Science.

### Work Experience:

**Engineering Control Supplies Ltd** (April 2019 to March 2023)

- → Project Manager
  - Managing projects from inception to completion in a precision engineering field under the Waterfall project management methodology.
  - Developing and reviewing project plans and schedules, forecasting and reporting on future and ongoing projects.
  - Working closely with cross-functional teams, vendors and stakeholders to ensure project success.

## Russell Cawberry Ltd (June 2017 to March 2019)

- → CAD & Planning Coordinator
  - Producing accurate 2D CAD drawings according to project requirements.
  - Maintaining drawing version control, ensuring all project stakeholders have access to the most up-to-date drawings.

Special Projects Ltd (January 2014 to June 2017)

- → Design Project Manager
  - Leading pre-works procurement, including bid preparation and submission, and managing project budgets.
  - Managing a small, multi-disciplinary team of designers, engineers, and contractors.
  - Attending project briefings, ensuring the project team is fully informed of project requirements and timelines.

#### Additional Qualifications:

- → IBM Python Basics for Data Science
  - Using Python and Pandas to analyse and visualise data in a Jupyter Notebook.
- → HarvardX CS50G Introduction to Game Development
  - ♦ Designing and creating 2D and 3D games using PyGame, Kaboom.js, Lua, LÖVE 2D, and Unity.
- → FreeCodeCamp Certificate in Responsive Web Design
  - ◆ Using HTML and CSS to make responsive web projects.
- → Alpha Academy PRINCE2 Foundation & Practitioner.
- → SPOCE AgilePM Practitioner
- → City & Guilds AutoCAD 2D Level 3
  - ◆ Certification to teach AutoCAD to an intermediate level.
- → Association for Project Management (APM) Associate Member